what's quickest in a drag race between a
tuned BMW M5 competition a tuned Audi
RS6 and a tuned Mercedes
e63s well we're going to find out
because I'm going to drag race them over
the standing quarter mile because I'm
Matt Watson and you're watching car wow
Buy sell car wow
so let me tell you about this BMW M5
which has been kindly linked to me by
DNA Autohaus they sell high-end cars
such as this it's got a 4.4 liter twin
turbo V8 however it's been tuned by
evolve Automotive as a result it now has
750 horsepower and 1000 newton meters of
torque drives all four wheels for an
8-speed automatic gearbox with launch
control it weighs in at just under
1.9 tons let's find out about the
Mercedes from its driver it's racing
driver Sam hello racing driver Sam hello
can you tell me about the car that you
were driving today please I am in a
Mercedes E63 I have got 810 horsepower
it's been MSL tuned which is basically
an ECU remap it's just under two tons so
it's a little bit heavy nine speed Auto
gearbox yeah should be fun and how much
torque is your four liter twin turbo V8
putting out my 4-liter twin turbo V8 is
putting out 1 000 newton meters of
torque do you see how I like managed to
just bring in the size of the engine
which you forgot to mention anyway let's
move to you Yanni tell us about your car
so I never mentioned the bunny is in the
rear window why didn't you mention them
first of all
are they part of the tuning upgrade I
think it's to go in his head anyway uh
RS6 4 liter twin turbo V8
750 horsepower 1000 newton meters it's
got that that wrench Source I've been
told so this should be quick all-wheel
drive 8-speed 2.1 tons and it's around
000 pounds let's see what happens in a
drag race but before we do we're gonna
do the sound check I'm going to rev up
this BMW
[Music]
now I've got a soft limiter at 5000 RPM
but this still
sounds pretty epic how about you yanny
let's have a listen to your car
it revs all the way around but
I don't know it just sounds all engine
and your Mercedes Samuel
it's uh got that silly soft limiter it's
nice on the overrip though it kind of
pops and bangs yeah
I think this one sounds the best I
concur I disagree just for the sake of
it mate you got a matte blue car mate
with bunny ears like you can't even talk
and red calipers yeah but when this wins
you're a matte black Batmobile you're
going to feel a bit stupid aren't you oh
it's gloss black mate should I get some
glasses
what are those two going on about anyway
if you haven't done so already make sure
you subscribe to this Channel and hit
the Bell icon to turn your notifications
on that way you won't miss a single
upload let's get and race
all right
[Applause]
[Music]
this thing just pushed through its
brakes on launch control yeah you
definitely jumped but this this wasn't
great on launch man at all yeah I
couldn't hold it I was like fought like
on the floor on the break and it was
just pushing through it anything from
you Sam yeah this launched well but it
felt bad because yours jumped well I
know now that you said it's pushed
through on the brakes that's not your
fault
there's always another inch I wish I had
another inch I don't think I got it
though
[Music]
yeah
better
yes this is bloody quick not gonna lie
this car is quick and that really up my
leg
but I won yeah I was pleased with that
launch just doesn't seem to have enough
sauce to catch you mate and Sam can we
get a uh a judge's decision on jumping
there please because uh I didn't even
see you Matt but yanny seemed a bit you
know enthusiastic Stewarts can you do
some stewarding please we've just had a
look and it was fine the start was good
oh there you go yummy you came second
mate yeah still not great but better
than nothing what sauce have you got in
your car what's yours mine's an evolve
tune 750 horsepower same as yours it's
just BMW horsepower is just a bit more
anyway Sam how you feeling well let's
have one more go and I'm gonna launch
correctly as well okay how's that I'm in
a BMW I'm gonna have to drive all the
way up the runway and all the way back
down again to just re-engage launch
control so be it worst jobs in the world
just get it done now I'll be back
waiting for you yeah
on this button we're going again
it's pointless mate honestly you're
gonna win I'm gonna come say he's gonna
come third he's just wasting our time
I'm beating yanny we're doing it again
let's put a bet on then if you're that
confident but you will not beat me let's
go let's do it bet on it is right bet on
it what you want to bet all right you go
run up there by the time we get back
down matt will come out of a plan a few
minutes later rather than do the whole
money thing for this bet let's have it
the loser
has to for the following races and
challenges have their driving seat in my
driving position and we all
we all am short and I sit too close to
the wheel so for the rest of the video
whoever loses between you two I will
come into your car set up your driving
position and you'll have to have it like
that for the rest of the video okay okay
but sounds shorter than me but okay
that's still fine didn't you say I sit
really far back though remember that
last day so I think it'll balance out
won't it you do you sit quite far back
like racing driver thing and I will set
it in a position that I deem appropriate
regardless okay so let's get on with
this race
don't believe it I don't believe it
oh that was said it's got a good launch
[Music]
the launch is dead on this man
might just set up Charlie's driving
position
[Music]
uh stewards can we check if he jumped
please
[Music]
well there you go yanny unfortunately
you're lost which means I'm going to
need to reset your driving position but
before I do that let's do the thing so
then what exactly happened well the BMW
won it completed the standing quarter
mile with a time of 10.5 seconds the
Mercedes took 10.8 seconds to do the
quarter mile the Audi was just behind
with a time of 10.9 seconds right now we
get into the rolling race but before we
do that let me reset janny's driving
position
thank you
oh my God look at this city as well like
a little Irish leprechaun right so Sam
you're used to me in my driving position
because you instruct me so let's just
make sure it's fair absolutely right
yeah so I'd like to be quite close very
close it's safer because there's got to
be a bend in your legs and your elbows
remember we discussed that yeah so that
feels about right the back rest you
normally have it higher because your
helmet don't you so
that's about right I feel really comfy
actually yeah it looks comfy that's
that's a good position the whole rest of
the video the entire video what actually
let's get the lumbar support in as well
get some of that in because you need
that because the lateral support is
important yeah let's get all that like
that's that's there as well
come on I want to watch this come on we
might need to push him in there come on
there it is there it is
no no wait I've seen some more
belt on Yanni's Safety First
you do not want that airbag to go off
what's yeah what's going on
right you can't move it all right
he looks really uncomfortable
you look good
perfect driving position look at my arms
right is everyone sitting comfortably
with a rolling race 50 miles an hour
causing Comfort mode automatic mode
Let's see what happens
three two one go
oh hello come on in my new driving
position
okay
[Applause]
I think your response is slightly
quicker than Jan when you're closer to
the wheel maybe that's what you've been
going wrong all these years yeah exactly
me exactly what I've been got yeah
exactly mate
are you putting the window down because
you're sweating it's hot in here man
it's hot Sam it was a loss for you
wasn't it but you still feel like you're
winning right yeah I'm winning in every
way but on track which is standard for
me anyway this had a really slow
lethargic kick down it'll be interesting
to see how it does in the manual race
because it you didn't get me but the
launch I just off the kick down you both
beat me well let's do that right now
then okay so now we're gonna do the
rolling race again 50 miles an hour over
the half mile this time no sportier
settings and manual mode third gear roll
on here we go three two one go
oh that RS6 shot off
in fact I'm losing
so I'm coming back but will I come back
oh
oh that was interesting that is where
you see the range Source mate that's
where it is mid-range real good I think
I might have just picked him at the line
you might have but that was that would
the cars finally turned up finally
finally how about you Sam what have you
got to say for yourself I mean it shot
off pretty well no to be fair Yanni's
shot off a little bit ahead of mine and
then there was like I don't know 200
yards where it was just gapping me and
then it leveled out so you're right it's
that mid-range yeah and that that's just
got lots of power yeah this thing like
the response wasn't great but once it's
found it's like legs it just absolutely
rocket and a real viewing and then I
think I just beat yanny on the line you
know enjoy the next test a lot though
Yanni because it's the brake test it's
gonna be really really Pleasant for you
but let's do it anyway when we reach the
line for emergency stop which car will
stop in the shortest distance and is he
only too close to the steering wheel
with find out
[Applause]
this one then the Audi and then the
Mercedes which is basically what has
happened in every other event except for
the one that mattered where I lost the
mat we must see it's like unbelievable
what's it like in that position is it a
horrendous was it hard to do the brake
test to be for it's not that bad but
yeah I feel very close to this steering
wheel I'm very conscious of the fact
that I'm steering wheel on windscreens
are very close Sam it wouldn't be a
cowboy drag race video if we didn't have
some excuses from you so what are your
final excuses for the day the bunny ears
there is an extra spoiler on the back of
this which is creating a lot of drag so
that's one hindrance and I think I was
on the bumpy side of the surface for
breaking but that's it I'll take that
that's fine perfect excuses I think
they're all completely invalid anyway if
you're after a high performance car and
you want to spend a little bit less than
one of these I've found one through
Carlo if you want to find out what the
car is and the deal click on the pop-out
banner up there or follow the link in
the description below anyway I want to
say a huge thanks to the guys that have
learned just their cars so follow them
on their Instagram accounts their
YouTube channels if they've got them
links are all in the description so
thank you everybody and I hope you all
enjoyed the video if you did give it a
like let me know which of these three
cars you would rather own click on those
windows there for some more videos and
on that box there to go to Carlow to
sell a car the easy way just upload some
photos give a brief description then
dealers all across the country will bid
on your car it's easy thanks for
watching